https://fccbrla.org/privacy-policy/

Privacy & Media Policies
Privacy Policy
About Our Site and Your Information
This website is maintained as a service to visitors, seekers, members, their families, and staff. The Privacy Policy set forth below governs your use of this website, and by using the website you agree to be bound by them. Therefore, please read the Privacy Policy carefully before you use this website. If you do not agree with our Privacy Policy, please do not use this website.
Usage Data
Like most websites, this website logs your IP address, browser type, visits to particular pages, and other general traffic information. The information we collect is not linked to personally identifiable information and you remain anonymous. We do not use this information for ads, nor is it ever released to any third party. We do use this information to provide and maintain our website, to monitor usage of our website, anticipate and address needs of our website visitors, and to detect, prevent, and address technical issues.
We may use third-party providers to monitor and analyze the use of our website. Google Analytics is a web analytics service offered by Google that tracks and reports website traffic. Google uses the data collected to track and monitor the use of our website. This data is shared with other Google services. Google may use the collected data to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network. You can opt-out of having made your activity on our website available to Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. The add-on prevents the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js, analytics.js, and dc.js) from sharing information with Google Analytics about visits activity. For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy & Terms web page: http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/
Gathering and Use of Personal Information
If you give us personal information for purposes of submitting a form, posting a comment or contributing text, subscribing to newsletter(s), managing your church record, contacting the church (collectively, our bases for collecting personal information), we will not share that information with any third party other than authorized employees, agents, or contractors who have agreed to keep information secure and confidential; or, in order to comply with the law; to enforce or apply the Privacy Policy or Terms of Use; or, to protect the rights, property or safety of the website, any user of the site, First Christian Church or any of its directors, officers, employees, agents or affiliated organizations. Information provided may be retained indefinitely. You may request that any information we have obtained be returned to you and/or deleted from our records.
Your information, including personal data, may be transferred to and/or maintained on, computers located outside of your state, province, country, or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ from those in your own jurisdiction. If you are located outside of the United States and choose to provide information to us, please be aware that information is transferred to the United States and processed there.
First Christian Church newsletters and list-style notices are sent through email management software, based on your subscription request submitted online, by email, or other means of personal request and approval. Your subscription information is not disclosed to any third party. Your subscription may be changed at your discretion. You may opt out of receiving any or all of our newsletters/list-style announcements at any time using the personal opt-out notification located at the bottom of every email.
Cookies
A “cookie” is a file that is sent from a web server to your web browser and placed on your computer. When you initially visit the website, we create a cookie for your computer and then use it to track your clicks as you go through the site. We also use cookies if users specify that they want the site to “store” their login information. There is no personal information stored within the cookie itself and we cannot use cookies to retrieve personal information about you or from your computer. While your activity may be tracked while you are at our website, we do not use cookies to track your activity before or after you leave the site. We use cookies to track page usage, usage patterns, downloads and to maintain an active connection for our administrators on the database.
Links to Other Sites
This privacy policy applies only to this website. This site contains links to websites that are not operated by First Christian Church. These links are provided for your reference and convenience only and do not imply any endorsement of the activities of these third-party websites or any association with their operators. First Christian Church does not control these websites and is not responsible for their data practices. We urge you to review the privacy policy posted on any site you visit before using the site or providing any personal data about yourself.
Children
First Christian Church does not knowingly collect personal data from children under the age of thirteen. If you are under thirteen, please do not give us any personal data. If you have reason to believe that a child has provided personal data to us without the advice and consent of their parent or legal guardian, please contact us, and we will delete that information from our website databases.
Changes to the Privacy Policy
This Privacy Policy may change from to time as website functionality, laws, and technology change. We encourage you to check this page frequently.
Posting of Personal Information
Please be aware that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online – for example, in a post, a form submission, or through email – that information can be collected and used by others. By disclosing personal information online, you may make that information available to others who may use it to send you unsolicited messages or for other purposes you may not desire or intend.
Terms of Service
Use of the website is at the user's sole risk, and it is provided without warranties of any kind, whether express or implied. We do not, and cannot, warrant that the website will function uninterrupted, secure, or available at any particular time or location, that or when any errors or defects may be corrected, that it is free of any viruses or other harmful components, or that the results of the using the website meet your requirements.
You represent that any content you post on the website is yours and/or you have right to use it and right to grant us the rights and license to post it, and that the posting of your content does not violate the privacy rights, publicity rights, copyrights, contract rights, or any other rights of any person or entity. You grant us the right and license to use, modify, publicly perform, publicly display, reproduce, and distribute such content on and through this website, and make the content available to other users who may also use your content subject to these terms.
Content found on this website is the property of First Christian Church or used with license/permission. You may not distribute, modify, transmit, reuse, download, repost, copy, or use said content, whether in whole or in part, without express advance written permission from First Christian Church.
Contact Information
If you have any questions regarding our Privacy Policy, you can send an email to the church office, or contact us at:
First Christian Church8484 Old Hammond HighwayBaton Rouge LA 70809Ph. 225-926-4175Email the church.
Media Policy
Photos and other media help tell the story of our vibrant community, enhance the quality of information we provide, and help visitors have an idea of what to expect when they attend our church.
We would like to share media items recorded at our various ministry activities, events and programs in church-produced materials including, but not limited to, brochures, newsletters, social media sites, and on the church website.
Accordingly, participation in church activities implies permission for publication of any media recorded, unless a “Media Opt-Out Form” has been submitted to the church office (below). While we reserve the right to photograph and record church events, in an effort to respect your privacy, we will strive to adhere to the following guidelines:
Any adult may complete the Media Images Opt-Out Form if they do not wish for media items in which they, vulnerable adults in their charge or the minor children for whom they are the parent/legal guardian are prominently featured to be used in publications produced by First Christian Church.
Anyone may request a particular media item which prominently features them or those for whom they are the parent/legal guardian be removed from use by submitting a request to the church office. All requests will be documented.
Special consideration for media images of minors (whether or not you opt-out):
No identifying information will accompany photos, including names, addresses, email addresses, family members’ names, or schools.
If a child is wearing a nametag in a photo, the nametag will be removed using photo editing software.
Images of individual minors will not be used to advertise future events without parental consent (a photo release form).  Large-group photos in which individual children cannot be identified are permissible.
Your Name (required)
Your Email (required)
